THE// FLATIRON SCHOOL





Li Ouyang

EMAIL: li.ouyang@gmail.com

PHONE: 857-212-5555

GITHUB: { http://github.com/styliii }

TWITTER: @styliii

MEETUP PRESENTATION:

+ Object-Oriented Design { http://vimeo.com/53181264 }

BLOG: { http://styliii.com/ }

+ How the Internet Works: Part 1 of 3 { http://bit.ly/RFTwmV }

+ Setting Up a Staging Environment to Use OmniAuth Facebook { http://bit.ly/QbBJVU }

Bio

Li Ouyang has 7 years of experience in finance as a derivatives trader at an investment bank. During market hours, she focused on managing risk. Outside of that, she sifted through heaps of data points, in hopes of uncovering patterns that would lead to fantastic risk/reward opportunities. As markets changed, she was able to successfully shift her money generating strategies.

Banking regulation changed the game and it was time for Li to shift her career. Thinking she would follow the footsteps of a friend into business development, she signed up for a number of startup related classes. However, it was a Ruby on Rails class that truly spoke to her drive to solve problems.

Li is currently a student at Flatiron School, where she's been honing her skills as a full stack web developer. When she's not coding, she's most likely teaching yoga and laughing.

Interests

- + Yoga
- + Dance
- + Antiquing
- + Finance
- + Medicine
- + Big Data

Notes	



Recent Technical Experience

HANDRAI.SE - a classroom version of StackOverflow

- + Devised and implemented workflow via state machine.
- + Implemented timed polling for dynamically refreshed navigation.
- + Used AJAX and jQuery to create a one-page experience.
- + Utilized Javascript's pushState and popState to deliver a normalized browser experience.

BINSAPP - source for online comics

- + Built the entire back end, using Ruby on Rails.
- + Implemented drag and drop functionality for multiple files and image uploading via Amazon
- + Implemented a multi-step form wizard with validations.

AIRBRAKE-DASHBOARD - a better approach to Airbrake

- + Built a custom Airbrake dashboard to filter noisy errors and custom token tags.
- + Integrated app with Airbrake API to allow two-way updating of error statuses.
- + Utilized NoSQL database (Mongo DB) for scalability and flexibility.

FLOATING JOURNEY - mood tracker

+ Integrated Twilio to send and receive text messages, allowing users to interact with app without ever touching a browser.

Education

TUFTS UNIVERSITY, Medford, MA Bachelor of Science in Mathematics and Quantitative Economics, 2005

Employment History

CLEARHEALTHCOSTS

New York

Strategic Consultant
July 2007 to January 2012

- + Formulated revenue strategy of selling advertisement space on website and created media kit.
- + Pitched ad space to potential small business clients.
- + Used SEO and Google Analytics to determine effectiveness of product design and content.

JPMORGAN CHASE

New York

Equity Trader, Vice President July 2007 to January 2012

- + Managed \$100mm in capital, generating more than 20% return with a 3 Sharpe ratio.
- + Researched, backtested and formulated trade strategies to monetize arbitrage opportunities in the market, centered around index volatility, dispersion, and relative value across sectors and global indices.
- + Trained and managed a junior analyst.

CITIGROUP

New York

Sales and Trading Analyst Sept 2005 to July 2007

- + Provided analytical risk tools on a daily basis to facilitate trading decisions
- + Collaborated with lawyers, marketers and traders to assist in deal preparation and execution.
- + Responsible for secondary trades of fund based structured products, which included executing trades and dealing with settlement issues.
- + Tracked competitor deals of registered equity structured products to produce league tables.

CORINIA ERICKA Baker